Finding Aid for Democratic Party of Michigan records, 1932-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Other Staff Positions
  - Press/Publicity
    - Topical Files 1965-1981
      - 1978
        - Campaigns and Elections
          - Ballot Proposals (Box 56)
          - Campaign Finance Reporting: miscellaneous copies of Bulletin and the Polling Place (Box 56)
          - Fitzgerald for Governor (Box 56)
          - Fitzgerald for Governor Promotional Film rip (Box 56)
          - Gubernatorial Primary (mostly clippings), 2 folders (Box 56)
          - Senate Democratic Campaign Workshop (Box 56)
          - Senatorial Primary (mostly clippings), 2 folders (Box 56)
          - Conventions and Conferences (Box 56)
          - Democratic National Party Midterm Conference (Box 56)
            (mostly re: Michigan Delegation Selection Plan)
        - State Fall Convention (Box 56)
        - Damman, James (clippings) (Box 56)
        - Democratic National Committee and Democratic National Party (clippings) (Box 56)
        - Fundraising: Sample Letters (Box 56)
        - Issues: Public and Legislative
          - Campaign Reforms (clippings) (Box 56)
          - Crime (mostly clippings) (Box 56)
          - Education (mostly clippings) (Box 56)
          - Environment and Department of Natural Resources (mostly clippings) (Box 56)
          - Michigan Mental Health Care (especially Plymouth Center; clippings) (Box 56)
          - Project ELF/Seafarer (mostly clippings) (Box 56)
          - Tax Reform (clippings), 2 folders (Box 56)
        - Michigan Congressmen (clippings) (Box 56)
        - Michigan Democrat: includes postal/circulation statements (Box 56)
        - Michigan Democratic Party (clippings) (Box 56)
        - Public Opinion (polls, articles, clippings) (Box 56)
      - 1979
        - Census-1980 (clippings) (Box 57)
        - Conventions and Conferences
          - Democratic 1980 National Convention Site Selection Committee
            - General (Box 57)
            - Clippings (Box 57)
          - State Spring Convention (Box 57)
        - County Strategy Session (Box 57)
        - Democratic Citizens Caucus (clippings and later material) (Box 57)
        - Democratic National Committee Newsletters (Box 57)
        - Fundraising
          - Meet the Michigan Majority (Box 57)
          - Sample Letters (Box 57)
        - Issues: Public and Legislative
          - Campaign Reforms (clippings) (Box 57)
          - Conflict of Interest in Government Legislation (summary and clippings) (Box 57)
          - Environment and Department of Natural Resources (mostly clippings) (Box 57)
          - Insurance Reform (clippings, reports) (Box 57)
          - Michigan Mental Health Care (including Plymouth Center, clippings) (Box 57)
          - Project ELF/Seafarer (clippings) (Box 57)
          - Sunset Legislation (Box 57)
            (clippings, Senators Blanchard and Corbin news releases)
          - Tax Reform (Box 57)
        - Michigan Congressmen (clippings) (Box 57)
        - Michigan Democrat (postal matters) (Box 57)
        - Michigan Democratic Party (clipping) (Box 57)
        - News/Press Advisories (includes undated) (Box 57)
        - Potential Newsletter/Newspaper Topics (Box 57)
      - 1980
        - Campaigns and Elections
          - Campaign Finance Reporting (Box 57)
          - Presidential (clippings), 2 folders (Box 57)
          - State: D.S.C.C. News Releases: Supreme Court and Education candidates (Box 57)
      - Conventions and Conferences
        - Democratic National Convention
          - Arrangements (Box 57)
          - County Caucus Training Session (Box 57)
          - Michigan Delegate Selection Plan (Box 57)
        - State Fall Convention (Box 57)
      - Fundraising: Sample Letters (Box 57)
      - Issues: Public and Legislative: Health Care Reform Legislation (Box 57)
      - Leadership Newsletter (miscellaneous copies and background material) (Box 57)
      - News/Press Advisories (Box 57)
      - Potential Newsletter/Newspaper Topics (clippings) (Box 57)
      - 1981
        - "Feedback III" (results of questionnaire on government) (Box 57)
        - Leadership Newsletter: miscellaneous copies and background material (Box 57)
        - Michigan Democrat: Letters to the Editor (Box 57)
        - News/Press Advisories (Box 57)
        - Reagan Policies: bulletins by various national Democratic Party organizations (Box 57)
    - Shirley Gray 1977-1980
      - Correspondence 1979-1980
        (includes miscellaneous Olivia Maynard correspondence)
        - 1979 (Box 57)
        - 1980 (Box 57)
      - Topical Files
        - Undated
          - Policy Committee (Box 57)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 57)
        - 1977
          - Policy Committee (Box 57)
        - 1978
          - Policy Committee (Box 57)
        - 1979
          - D.S.C.C. Meetings (Box 57)
          - Policy Committee (Box 57)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 57)
        - 1980
          - D.S.C.C. Meetings (Box 57)
          - Policy Committee (Box 57)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 57)
    - Jeff Ely 1982 Miscellaneous (Box 57)
  - Executive director (Tom Boyd) files 1990-1995
    - Anybody but Engler event 1993 (Box 58)
    - Apportionment plan (State House; U.S. House) 1992 (Box 58)
    - Convention: Rules Committee Report 1990 (Box 58)
    - Convention plan, etc. 1994 (Box 58)
    - Congressional districts
      - 4th (Box 58)
      - 8th (Box 58)
      - 10th (Box 58)
    - Coordinated campaign: A comprehensive proposal for the 1994 Michigan coordinated campaign, 1993 (Box 58)
    - Dresch, Stephen (Upper Peninsula state representative) (Box 58)
    - Election day (minority voter intimidation (Box 58)
    - F.A.I.R. campaign material (Box 58)
    - Greenberg Research. Democratic National Committee Michigan, a report January 1992 (Box 58)
    - Greenberg Research. Democratic National Committee Michigan, a report July 1993 (Box 58)
    - Platform 1990 (Box 58)
    - Presidential primary 1993 (Box 58)
    - State Central Committee, Policy Committee 1994 (Box 58)
    - State Convention: 1994 call (Box 58)
    - State Senate
      - Dinello, Gilbert 1994 (Box 58)
      - 36th District 1993 (Box 58)
      - 37th District 1994 (Box 58)
      - Coordinated campaign 1994 (Box 58)
  - Policy Committee Files (Libby Maynard) 1973-1974
    - General (Box 58)
    - Administration/Procedures (Box 58)
    - Agriculture, Ecology and Environment (Box 58)
    - Canvassing (Box 58)
    - Crime/Drugs (Box 58)
    - Economic Progress, Human Rights and Social Welfare (Box 58)
    - Education/Finance (Box 58)
    - Election Reform and Government (Box 58)
    - Foreign Policy (Box 58)
    - Hearings (Box 58)
    - Liaison with Local Committees (Box 58)
    - Polling (Box 58)
    - Sub-committees
      - Drafting/research (Box 58)
      - Issues (Box 58)
      - Operations (Box 58)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 58)
- Headquarters (Lansing) files 1951-1982
  The Headquarters files have been arranged into a yearly topical file. In addition to previous chairs, this accession contains files of chair Olivia Maynard (beginning in 1979). The files cover the years 1951 to 1981 and includes earlier files that had been retained by staff members.
  - Undated
    - By-Laws: Sample County and Township (Box 59)
    - Campaigns and Elections
      - House Campaign Coordinating Committee (Box 59)
      - Precinct Delegate Reference Material (Box 59)
      - State Special Elections (Box 59)
      - Voter Registration and Identification Forms (Box 59)
    - Chairperson
      - Chairperson's Report (Morley Winograd?) (Box 59)
      - Chairmanship Campaign (correspondence announcing candidacies) (Box 59)
      - Rules For Electing State Chairman (Box 59)
    - Committees, Councils, and Commissions
      - Commission on the Constitutional Convention (Box 59)
      - Economic Advisory Council (Box 59)
      - Platform and Resolutions Committee (procedures) (Box 59)
      - Policy Committee, 2 folders (Box 59)
      - Political Reform Commission (Box 59)
    - Consensus Caucus (Box 59)
    - Conventions and Conferences
      - State Conventions
        - Minority Report ("Who Shall Have The Power") (Box 59)
        - Program (dated 8/31) (Box 59)
        - Proportional Voting System (Box 59)
        - Resolutions circa 1964 (Box 59)
        - Tally Sheets (Box 59)
    - County Questionnaire (Box 59)
    - Dickenson, Kay (speeches) (Box 59)
    - Eighteen Year Old Vote circa 1971 (Box 59)
    - Ferency, Zolton (clippings) (Box 59)
    - Field Representative (clipping about Sue Jones) (Box 59)
    - Issues: Public and Legislative
      - Busing (Box 59)
      - Judges (appointment vs. election) (Box 59)
      - Tax Reform 1974-circa 1977 (Box 59)
    - Labor Lists (Box 59)
    - Land Use (research paper) (Box 59)
    - Maps (Box 59)
    - Meetings: Officers (Box 59)
    - Milliken, William (Box 59)
      (Senator Cooper, Morley Winograd, and [individual unknown] response to Milliken legislative program)
    - Party Informational Brochures (Box 59)
    - "The Pattern of American Politics" (no author) (Box 59)
    - PBB Resolution (Box 59)
    - Personnel Practices (Box 59)
    - Proposed Democratic Party Discussion Groups (Box 59)
      (Neil Staebler to Morley Winograd Memo)
    - Rules for Candidate Voting (Box 59)
    - Secretary's Notebooks (Mary Bethany?) (Box 59)
    - Speech: Democratic Gubernatorial Candidate (Box 59)
    - Volunteer Polling (Survey Director's Manual) (Box 59)
    - Winograd Commission ("...the Winograd Commission report as it relates to Michigan.") (Box 59)
    - Miscellaneous (Resolutions, Policy Committee?) (Box 59)
  - 1951
    - Fundraising: Jeff/Jack Program (Box 59)
  - 1961
    - Committees, Councils, and Commissions: Long-Term Planning Committee (Box 59)
  - 1962
    - Committees, Councils, and Commissions: Long-Term Planning Committee (Box 59)
  - 1964
    - Campaigns and Elections: Legislative Campaign Kit (Box 59)
    - Conventions and Conferences
      - State
        - Fall Convention, 2 folders (Box 59)
        - Spring Convention (Box 59)
    - Polls: Detroit News (Box 59)
  - 1965
    - Conventions and Conferences: State Spring Convention
      - General (Box 59)
      - Correspondence (Box 59)
      - County Resolutions (Box 59)
  - 1966
    - Campaigns and Elections: Senatorial Primary Procedures (Box 59)
    - Conventions and Conferences: State Fall Convention
      - General, 2 folders (Box 59)
      - Candidate Information (Box 59)
      - Committees' Reports (Box 60)
      - Correspondence (Box 60)
      - County and District Resolutions, 2 folders (Box 60)
      - News Clippings (Box 60)
      - Party Platform (Box 60)
    - County Checklist (Box 60)
    - Meetings: D.S.C.C. (Box 60)
  - 1967
    - Ferency, Zolton: clippings, including resignation as state party chairman (Box 60)
    - Meetings: D.S.C.C. (Box 60)
    - Michigan Federation of Teen Democrats (Box 60)
    - "Reference Book for Democratic County Leaders" (Box 60)
    - Ruppe, Philip E.: Voting Record (Box 60)
    - Secretary: Olivia Maynard: Correspondence (Box 60)
  - 1968
    - By-Laws: D.S.C.C. (includes 1968 amendments) (Box 60)
    - Campaigns and Elections
      - Correspondence: congratulations, condolences, thank you's (Box 60)
      - Presidential (Box 60)
        (includes D.S.C.C. news releases re: Hubert Humphrey)
    - Chairperson: Sander M. Levin ?: Speech (end of the year?) (Box 60)
    - Committees, Councils, and Commissions: By-Laws Committee (Box 60)
    - Conventions and Conferences
      - County (Box 60)
      - Democratic National Convention (Box 60)
        (includes Joseph Whitten statement re: selection of Michigan delegation)
      - Michigan Conference of Concerned Democrats (Box 60)
        (includes previous material)
      - State Fall Convention (Box 60)
      - State spring Convention (Box 60)
    - Ferency, Zolton (clippings) (Box 60)
    - Fundraising: correspondence regarding state party financial difficulties (Box 60)
    - Meetings
      - D.S.C.C. (Box 60)
      - Leadership (Box 60)
      - Officers (Box 60)
    - Party Membership (Box 60)
    - Polls: Detroit News (Box 60)
    - Ruppe, Philip E.: Voting Record (Box 60)
    - Summer Calendar (Box 60)
  - 1969
    - Committees, Councils, and Commissions
      - Apportionment Committee (meeting announcement) (Box 60)
      - By-Laws Committee (Box 60)
      - Legislative Liaison Committee (announcement of first meeting) (Box 60)
      - Political Reform Commission: News release re: establishment of the commission (Box 60)
      - Voter Motivation Committee (Box 60)
    - Conventions and Conferences: State Spring Convention (Box 60)
      (see also Secretary folder)
    - Ferency, Zolton (clippings) (Box 60)
    - Labor List (Box 60)
    - Leadership Newsletter (Box 60)
    - Meetings
      - D.S.C.C. (Box 60)
      - Leadership (Box 60)
    - Proposed Budget: D.S.C.C. (Box 60)
    - Resolutions of Appreciation (correspondence) (Box 60)
    - Ruppe, Philip E.: Voting Record (Box 60)
    - Secretary: Olivia Maynard: State Spring Convention (Box 60)
  - 1970
    - Chairperson: James McNeely: Biennial Report (Box 60)
    - Conventions and Conferences
      - County Conventions (Box 60)
      - State Fall Convention (Box 60)
    - Ferency, Zolton (clippings) (Box 60)
    - Issues: Public and Legislative: Busing (Box 60)
    - Labor List (Michigan AFL-CIO) (Box 60)
    - Meetings
      - D.S.C.C. (Box 60)
      - Leadership (Box 60)
    - Party Membership (Box 60)
    - Proposed Operating Budget: D.S.C.C. (Box 60)
    - Ruppe, Philip E.: Voting Record (Box 60)
  - 1971
    - Committees, Councils, and Commissions: Special Committee on Quality Integrated Education (Box 60)
    - Conventions and Conferences: State Spring Convention (Box 61)
      - General (Box 61)
      - Resolutions (Box 61)
    - Ferency, Zolton (clippings) (Box 61)
    - Fundraising
      - Jeff/Jack: correspondence between Olivia Maynard and Birch Bayh (Box 61)
      - 500 Club: correspondence between Olivia Maynard and Henry Jackson (Box 61)
    - Issues: Public and Legislative: Busing (Box 61)
    - Labor List (Box 61)
    - Meetings: Leadership (Box 61)
    - Polls: Detroit News (Box 61)
    - Resolution on Equality in Education Opportunity (Box 61)
    - Ruppe, Philip E.: Voting Record (Box 61)
    - Vice-Chairperson: Olivia Maynard: Correspondence (Box 61)
    - Women's Caucus (Box 61)
  - 1972
    - Campaigns and Elections
      - "Mobilizing the Youth Vote" (published by Michigan Frontlash, Inc.) (Box 61)
      - Presidential
        - General (miscellaneous correspondence) (Box 61)
        - McGovern For President (Box 61)
        - Precinct Delegate Presidential Preferences (selected counties) (Box 61)
        - Visitors' Schedules (Box 61)
        - "Voter Registration Manual" (published by the Democratic National Committee) (Box 61)
      - State: Education Candidates (Box 61)
      - Miscellaneous Election Results by County; includes 1968, 1970 information (Box 61)
    - Conventions and Conferences
      - Convention Dates (Box 61)
      - County Convention (clipping) (Box 61)
      - Democratic National Convention
        - General (Box 61)
        - "The Delegates of '72" (by Martin Pilsner, Political Editor, CBS News) (Box 61)
        - Michigan Delegation (Box 61)
      - "People's Lib" (Democratic Women of Michigan and Wayne County Federation of Democratic Women) (Box 61)
    - State
      - Fall Convention (Box 61)
      - Spring Convention
        - General (Box 61)
        - Pre-Convention Resolutions Committee (Box 61)
    - Democratic National Committee (includes undated items) (Box 61)
    - Ferency, Zolton (Box 61)
      (Human Rights Party News Releases and Ferency statement to Michigan Legislature re: political public opinion polls)
    - Fundraising (miscellaneous correspondence) (Box 61)
    - Issues: Public and Legislative: Busing (Box 61)
    - Jeffrey, Mildred (Box 61)
      (announcement not to seek reelection to the Democratic National Committee)
    - Leadership Newsletter (Box 61)
    - Meetings
      - D.S.C.C. (Box 61)
      - Leadership (Box 61)
    - Northwestern Michigan Democratic Women's Club (Box 61)
      (organizational meeting attended by Olivia Maynard)
    - Officer and Staff Reorganization Assignments (Box 61)
    - Party Membership: Proposed student, commissioned membership drive (Box 61)
    - Polls: Detroit News (Box 61)
    - Ruppe, Philip E.: Voting Record (Box 61)
    - Vice-Chairperson: Olivia Maynard: Democratic National Committee Post Campaign/Election Politics (Box 61)
    - Women's Caucus (Box 61)
      (correspondence regarding Democratic National Convention delegate selection plan)
  - 1973
    - Campaigns and Elections: "Brochure Campaign" (Box 61)
    - Committees, Councils, and Commissions: Appeals Committee (Box 61)
    - Conventions and Conferences
      - Democratic Midwestern Regional Conference (Box 61)
      - Michigan Educational Association Conference (statement) (Box 61)
      - State Spring Convention (Box 61)
    - Damman, James (clippings, includes undated) (Box 61)
    - Democratic National Telethon (Box 61)
    - District Workshop Announcement (Box 61)
    - Fundraising
      - Jeff/Jack (Box 61)
      - 500 Club (membership list) (Box 61)
    - Labor List (Box 61)
    - Leadership Newsletter (Box 61)
    - Meetings: D.S.C.C. (Box 61)
    - Michigan Democratic Party (Box 61)
      (four page history of party growth)
    - Milliken, William (news releases) (Box 61)
    - Party Membership (county membership check list) (Box 61)
    - Proposed Personnel Practices: D.S.C.C. (Box 61)
    - Ruppe, Philip E.: Voting Record (Box 61)
    - Vice-Chairperson: Olivia Maynard: Democratic National Committee (Box 61)
  - 1974
    - Black Membership: D.S.C.C. (Box 61)
    - Campaigns and Elections
      - General (Box 61)
      - Campaign Workshop (Box 61)
        (held by the Democratic National Committee, and attended by Morley Winograd)
      - "Evaluation of The Scheduling Area" (by Sue Jones, written on February 10, 1975) (Box 61)
      - Levin For Governor (Box 61)
      - Primary Guidelines (Box 61)
      - "Some Preliminary Conclusions on The 1974 Michigan Gubernatorial Election" (author unknown, written January 6, 1975) (Box 61)
    - Committees, Councils, and Commissions: Policy Committee (subcommittee position statement on Watergate) (Box 61)
    - Conventions and Conferences: State Fall Convention, 2 folders (Box 61)
      (see also Secretary)
    - Damman, James (mostly clippings and news releases) (Box 61)
    - Ferency, Zolton (mostly clippings) (Box 61)
    - Fundraising: Jeff/Jack
      - General (Box 61)
      - Recap Sheets (Box 62)
    - Labor Lists (Box 62)
    - Meetings: D.S.C.C. (Box 62)
    - Milliken, Williams (clippings, office news releases) (Box 62)
    - Party Preference (Box 62)
      (national survey, includes results for Michigan)
    - Party Rules (includes later material) (Box 62)
    - Polls: Detroit News (Box 62)
    - Proposed Budget: D.S.C.C. (Box 62)
    - Ruppe, Philip E.: Voting Record (Box 62)
    - Secretary: Mary Bethany: Notebooks (Box 62)
    - Volunteer Polling Project (Box 62)
    - Women's Caucus (includes undated) (Box 62)
    - Youngblood, Charles (Box 62)
      (news releases concerning his conviction for felony)
  - 1975
    - Business and Professional Organizations (memo re:) (Box 62)
    - Campaign and Elections
      - General (Box 62)
      - House Campaign Coordinating Committee (Box 62)
    - Chairperson: Morley Winograd: Schedule August 4-August 23, 1975 (Box 62)
    - Committees, Councils, and Commissions: Policy Committee (Box 62)
    - Conventions and Conferences: State Spring Convention
      - General (Box 62)
      - County District Resolutions (Box 62)
      - Resolutions Adopted (Box 62)
      - Rules Committee (Box 62)
    - Damman, James
      - General (clippings, correspondence) (Box 62)
      - Attorney General's Report (Box 62)
    - Democratic County Leadership Handbook (includes "Rules of The Michigan Democratic Party") (Box 62)
    - Democratic National Committee: Michigan Affirmative Action Plan (Box 62)
    - Flory, Al (statistician): correspondence and reports (Box 62)
    - Fundraising
      - Jeff/Jack (Box 62)
      - Meet the Michigan Majority (Box 62)
    - Leadership Newsletter (Box 62)
    - Meetings
      - D.S.C.C. (Box 62)
      - Leadership Select Group (Box 62)
    - Party Membership (records) (Box 62)
    - Ruppe, Philip E.: Voting Record (Box 62)
    - Temporary Operating Budget (Box 62)
    - Women's Caucus (Box 62)
  - 1976
    - Campaigns and Elections
      - General (Box 62)
      - "Analysis of Recent Polls" August 8, 1976 (prepared by the Democratic National Committee) (Box 62)
      - Ballot Referenda (Cambridge Survey Research) (Box 62)
      - Campaign Finance Laws: Federal and State (Box 62)
      - Election Calendars (Box 62)
      - Get Out The Vote
        - General, 4 folders (Box 62)
        - General, 4 folders (Box 63)
        - Phone Tally Sheets (Box 63)
      - Mini-Retreat re: Campaign Law Changes (correspondence) (Box 63)
      - State Congressional Races (mostly re: Brouillette for Congress) (Box 63)
      - State-Wide Campaign Information (Box 63)
      - Visitor's Schedules (Box 63)
    - Charter Administration: Talent Inventory Program (Box 63)
    - Chairperson: Morley Winograd: Correspondence with Other State Chairs (Box 63)
    - Committees, Councils, Conventions
      - Con-Con Commission (constitutional convention) (Box 63)
      - Election Reform Legislation Committee (Box 63)
    - Conventions and Conferences
      - Democratic National Convention, 2 folders (Box 63)
        (mostly re: Michigan delegation selection, includes profiles of 1964 and 1976 Michigan delegates prepared by Barbara Farah and M. Kent Jennings)
      - State Fall Convention (Box 63)
    - Ferency, Zolton (mostly clippings) (Box 63)
    - Field Representative: Sue Jones: Correspondence (Box 63)
      (includes memo on Telethon 75 and Telethon 76-Upper Peninsula, miscellaneous Morley Winograd correspondence, and undated)
    - Finances: D.S.C.C.
      - Financial Statements (miscellaneous) (Box 63)
      - Transactions with County Parties (Box 63)
    - Flory, Al (correspondence and reports) (Box 63)
    - Fundraising: Jeff/Jack (mostly sales figures) (Box 63)
    - Hart, Peter D., Research Associates (correspondence and proposal for post-election survey) (Box 63)
    - Issues: Public and Legislative: Crime (Box 63)
    - Local Party Leadership Mini-Retreat (memorandum and agenda) (Box 63)
    - Meetings: D.S.C.C. (Box 63)
    - Michigan Spanish Speaking Democrats (meetings announcement) (Box 63)
    - Milliken, William (includes Cambridge Survey Research findings) (Box 63)
    - Party Membership
      - Disclosure List (Box 63)
      - Records, 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Party Platform (Box 63)
      (includes Amendments and copy of Recommended Party Platform)
    - Polls: Detroit News (Box 63)
    - Vice-Chairperson: Olivia Maynard: Correspondence
      - General (Box 63)
      - Democratic National Committee (Box 63)
    - Women's Caucus (Box 63)
  - 1977
    - Campaigns and Elections
      - Campaign Finance Reporting (Box 64)
      - Get Out The Vote (Box 64)
      - House Campaign Coordinating Committee (Box 64)
      - Primary Voters Guide (published by Civic Searchlight, Inc.) (Box 64)
      - State Election Laws (Box 64)
      - Special Elections Task Force (Box 64)
      - State Special Elections (Box 64)
    - Chairperson: Morley Winograd
      - Association of State Democratic Chairs: "Dollars for Democrats" Fundraising Project (Box 64)
      - Correspondence
        - General (Box 64)
        - Democratic National Committee Related Matters (Box 64)
        - Michigan Attorney General (Box 64)